The most dreaded Nazi of them all!
Ilsa: She Wolf of the SS is a thriller, horror,
war film directed by Don Edmonds.
Ilsa, a warden at a Nazi death camp that conducts experiments on prisoners, strives to prove that women can
withstand more pain and suffering than men, and therefore should be allowed to fight on the frontlines.
Ilsa, played by Dyanne Thorne.
Wolfe, played by Gregory Knoph.
Mario, played by Tony Mumolo.
Anna, played by Maria Marx.
Kata, played by Nicolle Riddell.
Ingrid, played by Jo Jo Deville.
Ilsa, She Wolf of the SS is a 1975 Canadian nazisploitation film about a
sadistic and sexually voracious Nazi prison camp commandant.
The film is directed by American filmmaker Don Edmonds and produced by David F.
Friedman for Cinépix Film Properties in Montreal.
The film stars Dyanne Thorne in the title role, who is loosely based on Ilse Koch, a
convicted war criminal and overseer at the Buchenwald concentration camp.
Upon its release in early 1975, the film was immediately met with widespread controversy and critical
derision, with Gene Siskel calling it "the most degenerate picture I have seen to play downtown".
Particular criticism was directed at the film's graphic violence, which includes depictions of
castration, flagellation, human experimentation, and many other forms of torture.
Word of mouth quickly spread, and the film was a considerable financial
success, becoming a staple of grindhouse and drive-in theaters.
The popularity of the film led to the creation of three
sequels, each of which saw Thorne reprise her role.
The film's infamy eventually evolved into a considerable cult following, with the character of Ilsa
becoming a pop cultural icon ubiquitous with "strong, aggressive" female authority.
The film is considered one of the prominent entries of the Nazi exploitation
sub-genre, and to a lesser degree the sexploitation sub-genre.
The film explores themes of rape, experiment, nazi, germany, sadism.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.